- jamesbin265988@outlook.com
- ☆ Jameson Thomas, United State
- +1 952 373 5638

About me

Prolific, Front end web developer with a passion for metrics and beating former "best-yets.", Well-versed in Front-End development. Recently throughout my 3 years career as a software developer I've focused on developing scalable and well documented code. I enjoy working collaboratively but can also run with projects on my own. Decreased rework by 18% and costs by 12% and consistently receive high user experience scores for all web development projects.

Skills

HTML, CSS, Javascript, JQuery

React, Next.js

Angular, Vue.js

Git, GitHub, GitBucket

Linux (Ubuntu, CentOS)
Administration

AWS, MS Azure devOps, Vagrant

Docker, Kubernetes

Education

Bachelor of Science (BS), Computer science

Saint Johns River State College, United State 2009 - 2013

Jameson Thomas

Front-end Developer

Work experience

Frontend developer

From November 2016 to September 2017 LEONI

- This company offer web development and graphic design services.
- I was responsible for design mockups, content management and React theme customization. Most of the React work was theme configuration and CSS changes.
- Maintained graphic standards and branding throughout the product's interfaces.

React Developer

From October 2017 to April 2019 Luxoft

- Worked on React and Node.js, Implemented websites, mobile applications, and landing pages from concept through deployment.
- Standardized all output with a new, responsive, mobile-first approach and strategy.
- Assessed UX and UI designs for technical feasibility.
- Developed standard and ad hoc reports in graph format as required.
- Collaborated with product team members to implement new feature developments.

Full stack Developer

From April 2019 to May 2021 Baker Tilly US

- We primarily used MERN Stack. 60% of my work was doing front end development, 20% back end development and the remaining 20% was dev-ops/sys admin related tasks. We had a few system admins for a 50 persons + company.
- I was occasionally asked to do things such as migrating test database data between environments, doing jenkins builds/minor build plan tweaks, configuring webpack/or ui/unit testing frameworks.

Frontend Developer

From September 2021 to January 2023 Livingstone Research

- I was invited as a team leader at this company, Collaborated with 6 web developers, project manager, graphics designer, two QA engineers of the Livingstone company based on daily meeting & discussion, periodically updates via GitHub. Worked as senior development leader in a team.
- Mentored 4 new junior front-end developers on team in expanding JavaScript, React, and Angular skillset.
- Rewrote HTML to meet industry and company standards for SEO and Accessibility.
- Git Manage: Worked on sub-branch, Review code and merge to main branch.